{
    "id": "73226200be434ab1a1ebe432ca1d4ea9",
    "title": "Tenses In Subordinate Clauses",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I will lend it to you on condition that you ……………………… it back tomorrow.",
            "description": "Present tenses are often used instead of will + infinitive to refer to the future in subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "bring",
                "will bring",
                "would bring"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "63510129f486454b8f5ff3a668f6446b"
        },
        {
            "question": "It will be interesting to see whether he …………………………… it or not.",
            "description": "Present tenses are often used instead of will + infinitive to refer to the future in subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "completes",
                "will complete",
                "would complete"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3254aaf71d024712a72264d91a06eb5b"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will call you when I ………………………..",
            "description": "Present tenses are often used instead of will + infinitive to refer to the future in subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "have finished",
                "will have finished",
                "had finished"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6fc5a433f35b48e5a42f6ed769e9256b"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t know where I ………………………… tomorrow.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the present tense, we use a future tense in the subordinate clause to refer to future.",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "would be",
                "will be"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "733c7699ba274e9ab604bee17e6874b8"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have bought a chicken in case Peter ……………………………….",
            "description": "We normally use a present tense with a future meaning after in case.",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "will arrive",
                "arrives"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "437e8431944c4952bb07604feeb452a2"
        },
        {
            "question": "It doesn’t matter where we ………………………… on holiday.",
            "description": "Present tenses are also used with a future meaning after it doesn’t matter.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "went",
                "will go"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "474292b21c2942ae8c8c5ed289b24785"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t care what we ……………………….. for dinner as long as I don’t have to cook it.",
            "description": "Present tenses are also used with a future meaning after I don’t care.",
            "answers": [
                "had",
                "have",
                "will have",
                "would have"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "97d22d308ee945f8876db21544115d62"
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked whether she ………………………… any message for me.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we will typically need a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "had",
                "will have"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4bcf8a585e11473085302dc7bb2cf0e3"
        },
        {
            "question": "We wish that it ……………………….. forever.",
            "description": "We usually use a past tense after wish to talk about something unreal or unlikely.",
            "answers": [
                "will rain",
                "had rained",
                "would rain"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5e7b1cd5714b4a11a26d84d308ffc2d8"
        },
        {
            "question": "I wish tomorrow ………………………… Sunday.",
            "description": "We usually use a past tense after wish to talk about something unreal or unlikely.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a944e851beeb4d69a290abefc04561ca"
        },
        {
            "question": "It’s time the children ……………………….. to bed.",
            "description": "We use a past tense after it’s time with a present meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "went",
                "go",
                "have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "319622e9572643a48ab2c30d90b93684"
        },
        {
            "question": "You had better ……………………… before I call the police.",
            "description": "We use the infinitive without to after had better.",
            "answers": [
                "leave",
                "left",
                "to leave"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "904d063208864c1eb752cfa873b15230"
        }
    ]
}